DENIS OTIENO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PERSONAL INFORMATION

NAME: DENIS OUMA OTIENO

PHONE: 0707-896-082

ID NO: 33229020

EMAIL ADDRESS: <u>dennisouma96@gmail.com</u>

LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/denis-otieno-33a8a9143

GENDER: Male

RELIGION: Christian

LANGUAGE: English, Kiswahili and Luo

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a dedicated and result driven professional in the field of ICT with two-plus years working experience in different ICT sectors.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

Through my 2 year-plus career as a software developer, I have focused on developing scalable and well documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects independently. Excited about the prospect of joining a product driven company.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

DATES	SCHOOL	ACHIEVEMENTS
2015- 2019	University of Eldoret	Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (IT)

SKILLS

SKILL	TECHNOLOGIES	ACHIEVEMENTS	
Software	Html 5 & CSS (CSS3, Bootstrap)	I have a couple of projects in	
Engineering	JavaScript (ES6, jQuery, React.js Express.js,	my toolkit and am a great Full-	
	Node.js,) Cloud (AWS),MongoDB	stack developer.	

UI/UX Designing	CorelDraw, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma	An artistic UI/UX Designer
IT Support Specialist	Windows and Unix OS computers Windows server Wired and wireless networks	I am very good at maintaining data centers, identifying, diagnosing and resolving technical issues.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATE	ORGANIZATION	RESPONSIBILITIES
Oct. 2021 - Sep. 2022	Ministry of Education	 Built RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on dynamically chosen user inputs. Tested software for bugs and operating speed, fixing bugs and documenting processes to increase efficiency. Support of E-Learning and content development in line with the schemes of work Support implementation of the Digital Literacy Programme Carrying out innovations to enable schools improve on use of digital learning
Jan. 2020 – Sep. 2021	Top and Up Enterprise, Kisumu, Kenya	 Developed creative design for marketing packages, including print materials, brochures, banners and signs. Completed in-depth product design tests with help of different software, models and design systems. Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones. Applied knowledge of production to produce high quality images.
May 2018 - August 2018	County Government of Kisumu	 Supported Network Administrator handling technology rollout and maintenance. Built and provided basic end-user troubleshooting and desktop support on Windows, Linux and Mac systems. Installed, modified and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues. Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and use processes. Monitored 2 windows servers, network connections, firewalls and corporate filters to maintain maximum up-time and functionality.